

Jacob A. Gorneau

GRADUATE STUDENT · ENTOMOLOGIST

Institute for Biodiversity and Sustainability, California Academy of Sciences

□+1 (518) 487-9889 | ☑jgorneau@gmail.com | ★ www.jacobgorneau.github.io | ᡚjacobgorneau | ᡚjacobgorneau

| 💆 @jacobgorneau | 🖸 0000-0001-9230-9774

Summary_

Graduate student at the California Academy of Sciences. Over 5 years experience working in museum collections doing research, curation, and arthropod identification. Experienced in a variety of field and lab techniques as well as science communication to a variety of audiences. Interested and passionate about arthropod diversity, evolution, and conservation.

Experience ____

Research Assistant Cornell University

Dr. LINDA S. RAYOR AND DR. CORRIE MOREAU

February 2019 — Present

· Completed Senior Honor's Research Thesis studying the social and life-history evolution of huntsman spiders; manuscript in review.

Research Assistant Cornell University Insect Collection

Dr. Jason J. Dombroskie

August 2016 — Present

• Described Neotropical species of Argyresthia (Lepidoptera: Argyresthiidae) from Guatemala, in preparation for publication.

Curatorial Assistant Cornell University Insect Collection

DR. JASON J. DOMBROSKIE

August 2016 — June 2020

- Undergraduate lead on an NSF-funded grant to curate the macrolepidoptera and database John G. Franclemon's slide collection of moth genitalia and corresponding specimens.
- Three families curated, totalling over 6,000 species, with curation protocol set in place ongoing for existing curation projects.

Lab Assistant Cornell University

DR. BRYAN N. DANFORTH

August 2018 — March 2020

• Worked to identify thousands of bees collected by New York State Department of Environmental Conservation for the Empire State Native Pollinator Survey, a project of the New York Natural Heritage Program.

Curatorial Assistant Cornell University

Dr. Laura Harrington

January 2019 - May 2019

• Curated and inventoried Cornell University Medical and Veterinary Entomology Collection, containing over 9,600 specimens and 665 species, including medically important arthropods, diseases, and conditions.

Lab Assistant & Museum Preparator

Cornell Universit

Dr. Linda S. Rayor

June 2017 — January 2018

• Trained in arthropod husbandry practices, including maintenance of live arachnids and insects. Collaborated with a team that collected and prepared over 350 dried spider specimens prepared in a lifelike position for The Australian Museum's *Spiders: Fear and Fascination* traveling museum exhibit.

Skills

Molecular DNA Extraction, PCR Amplification & Optimization, Gel Electrophoresis, Sanger Sequencing

Programming R (including R Markdown), Python (limited), LaTex (limited)

Digital Platforms Google Sites, GitHub Pages, Weebly, WordPress, Social Media Management (Twitter, Instagram, Facebook) **Computational** Molecular phylogenetic programs (Mesquite, Geneious, PopART, MrBayes, RAxML, IQ-TREE), GIS (limited)

Languages English, Latin (proficient, from High School)

Education

Master's in Biology, California Academy of Sciences (CAS)

CONCENTRATION: ECOLOGY, EVOLUTION, AND CONSERVATION BIOLOGY

San Francisco State University

August 2020 — December 2022

Bachelor's in Entomology

Cornell University

MAGNA CUM LAUDE, WITH DISTINCTION IN RESEARCH

August 2016 — May 2020

September 2021 Jacob A. Gorneau · Résumé